budgettravel.ie 2018-11-09

# Privacy Policy - Budget Travel

Club Travel limited and its associated companies is committed to ensure that all personal data processed by us is done so in accordance with the data protection laws and its principles, along with any associated regulations and/or codes of conduct laid down by the Supervisory Authority and local law. We ensure the safe, secure, ethical and transparent processing of all personal data and have stringent measures to enable data subjects to exercise their rights. Our website Privacy Statement sets out what information we collect, how we collect it, what we do with it and how we protect this information.

This Privacy Policy applies to the operations of the following websites;

[www.clubtravel.ie](http://www.clubtravel.ie/); [www.go4less.ie](http://www.go4less.ie/); [www.budgettravel.ie](https://www.budgettravel.ie/); [https://usa.budgettravel.ie](https://usa.budgettravel.ie/); [www.budgetair.ie](http://www.budgetair.ie/); [www.abbeytravel.ie](http://www.abbeytravel.ie/); [www.escape2.ie](http://www.escape2.ie/); [www.hotelinstyle.com](http://www.hotelinstyle.com/); [www.eurasiatravel.ie](http://www.eurasiatravel.ie/); [www.clubtravelhrg.com](http://www.clubtravelhrg.com/); [www.flightpixie.co.uk](http://www.flightpixie.co.uk/); [www.esta-usa.ie](http://www.esta-usa.ie/); [www.etavisa-australia.ie](http://www.etavisa-australia.ie/);

##  Collection of Personal Data

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with the best and most useful content to help improve your online experience. In order to process your booking, we collect personal details from you together with information we learn about you from your use of our website and other websites accessible through our website. These details may include (where applicable) passenger names, addresses, passport or Government issued EU National ID card numbers, telephone numbers, e-mail and IP addresses, credit/debit card or other payment details, travel behaviour. In some instances we may also collect information regarding medical conditions (only for passengers who have special medical requirements) which may affect the chosen flight arrangements.

We may use your personal information to identify you as a customer, to process your booking, to verify credit or other charge card details (if applicable) and to deliver relevant information to you in connection with your travel and any ancillary services which you may wish to avail of. Your information may also be used for immigration and customs control (see further below), security, crime prevention/detection, administrative and legal purposes. For these purposes, we may transmit your personal information to our own offices, authorised agents, other carriers and service providers, credit and charge card companies, data processing companies working on our behalf and to government agencies. Some of these entities may be located outside the European Economic Area. Your personal information and any records relating to your air travel will also be retained for audit functions.

Laws in force in the USA require Club Travel Limited and its associated companies to collect certain information from all passengers travelling to and from the USA, prior to travel. This information includes information held in the machine-readable zone (MRZ) of your passport (passport number, country of issue, passport expiry date, given names, last name, gender and date of birth) together with other information which is not held in the MRZ of your passport (country of residence, citizenship, alien registration card number, destination address in the USA travel agents. The information will be retained for at least three years and six months and may be shared with other authorities.

##  Sharing information about you

We follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of passenger information. Our security procedures require that we request proof of identity before we disclose sensitive information regarding your flight reservation.

We may disclose your information to trusted contracted companies who act as "data processors" on our behalf for the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement

We may share your information with trusted third parties for the purpose of collecting feedback and reviews about your booking experience with Club Travel and it's associated companies.

We may also pass your information on to government authorities or enforcement bodies for compliance with legal requirements.

In addition, under U.S. Law, U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) will receive certain travel and reservation information, known as Passenger Name Record or PNR data, about passengers flying between the European Union and the U.S. CBP has undertaken that it uses this PNR data for the purposes of preventing and combating terrorism and other transnational serious crimes. The PNR may include information provided during the booking process or held by airlines or travel agents. The information will be retained for at least three years and six months and may be shared with other authorities.

For booking purposes, we may disclose your information to trusted third-party ancillary service providers such as hotel, car hire and credit card providers for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement.

Club Travel Limited and its associated companies operate businesses in multiple jurisdictions, some of which are not located in the European Economic Area (EEA). While countries outside the EEA do not always have strong data protection laws, we will ensure that Club Travel Limited and its associated companies, and our services providers process your information in a secure manner and in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

##  Direct Marketing Material

From time to time we may contact you with information regarding travel information and ancillary products via email or SMS. You will have the choice to opt-in or opt-out and we will provide opt-out options on all direct marketing material when you no longer wish to receive our marketing material.

##  Site Tracking

To improve our service to you and to provide we use analytics software provided by a third party that generates an anonymous a cookie.  (Click here for the Club Travel and its associated companies Cookie Policy) These cookies can tell us whether or not you have visited the site before. Your browser will tell us if you have these cookies, and if you don't, we generate new ones. This allows us to track how many individual unique users we have, and how often they visit the site. Unless you are signed in to a Club Travel site, or the website of one of its associated companies, these cookies cannot be used to identify individuals; they are used for statistical purposes only. If you are logged in, we will also know the details you gave to us for this, such as username and email address.

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you wish, you can set your browser to prevent it from accepting cookies. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. The cookies we use do not detect any information stored on your computers.

For more information about cookies and how to stop cookies being installed visit the following website: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

##  Links to Third Party Websites

Links on this Website and other websites that we operate may lead to third party websites. The content, accuracy and function of such websites is outside of our control and we cannot accept any responsibility for same and nor do we endorse the contents of such third-party websites. In particular, any dealings that you have with such third-party website operators shall be on the terms and conditions (if any) of that website operator, as this privacy notification is limited to our websites. If you have a concern regarding the way your personal information will be used on other sites or on the type of cookies used and how they are being used then you are advised to read the relevant privacy statement and cookie policy or in the absence of such a statement and policy on the site, contact the company concerned. Any data stored by third party websites are stored completely separately by third party.

##  Security

When you purchase flights online or access your personal profile you can do so through a secure server. The use of Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology means that all personal information, such as your credit card number, will be encrypted as it travels from your computer to the Club Travel Online Booking Engine, or the booking engine of one of its associated companies. When received, the information is decrypted and processed in the same way as a normal credit card transaction by telephone.

If your browser supports SSL, and if you entered our site via our secure server access, then transmission of any sensitive data will be protected. If your browser does not support SSL, we recommend that you upgrade to the latest version of any browser to enhance the security of further transactions, otherwise the transmission of your personal data may not be protected and Club Travel and its associated companies disclaim any responsibility in this regard.

##  Your Rights

You may request at any time a copy of the personal information held about you and request its correction or deletion. To obtain a copy of this information please forward the required documents by mail post, or in person, to our Security and Compliance Department (See contact information).

For this purpose, you must provide the following documents:

  * A signed request;
  * A copy of your passport or national ID, so that we can verify your identity;
  * A signed authority from any third party whose data you request on their behalf.

Upon receipt of your request and within one month of receipt, we will inform you about the type of personal information we hold about you, the purposes for which we hold it and the possible recipients or types of recipients, as well as a copy of such data.

##  Changes to this Statement

If there are updates to the details of this Privacy Notification, we will post those changes and update the revision date at the top of this document, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have.

##  Data Protection in Ireland

More information on data privacy rights is available directly from the website of the Data Protection Commissioner [https://dataprotection.ie](https://dataprotection.ie/)

##  Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notification, wish to make a complaint or want to make an information request please contact us through our Security and Compliance email address at [datacompliance@clubtravel.ie](mailto:datacompliance@clubtravel.ie) or write to us at:

Security and Compliance Department

Club Travel limited

30 Lower Abbey street

Dublin 1

Ireland
